<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Willeeh's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://willeeh.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://willeeh.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-09T16:15:24+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://willeeh.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Guillermo Ceballos]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[tmux - terminal multiplexer]]></title>
    <link href="http://willeeh.github.io/blog/2013/07/07/tmux/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T23:29:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://willeeh.github.io/blog/2013/07/07/tmux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve found a great tool that belongs to a context I&rsquo;ve not been interested until now. Lately me and my coworkers team in <a href="http://www.mymalcom.com">Malcom</a> have been involved in dev-ops work. Connecting to many servers at the same time to look into logs, editing scripts, configurations, etc. is a everyday work. I used to launch terminals and handling them separately. Not anymore.</p>

<p>Here <a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net/">Tmux</a> comes to us to give a hand. It&rsquo;s a terminal multiplexer letting you run various TTYs in the same terminal window.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are two main behaviours to work with it, windows and panes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Windows behaviour lets you have various terminals in a unique terminal like tabs in a browser.</li>
<li>Pane behaviour lets you split the current window into panes.</li>
</ul>


<p>Let&rsquo;s go to work a little bit with it. Easy to install as usual thanks to <a href="http://mxcl.github.io/homebrew/">Homebrew</a> (only if you are in a Mac). If so, type in your terminal the following:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>brew install tmux</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now you can start up tmux. You know you are in tmux because you will see a green status bar that indicates where are you.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>tmux</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>You need to know tmux uses an action binding key <code>Ctrl + b</code> which you&rsquo;ll need to do any action you want. Start creating a new window with <code>Ctrl+b c</code>. Now you are in a second window if you want to go back to the previous window <code>Ctrl+b p</code>. Let&rsquo;s play with this keybindings list:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Ctrl+b c Create new window
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b n Move to the next window
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b p Move to the previous window
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b & Kill the current window
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b , Rename the current window
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b ? List all keybindings</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>But tmux supports another powerful feature, the second behaviour I mentioned: panes. You can split any window to panes, vertically and horizontally. Try with <code>Ctrl+b %</code> and you split the windows vertically. If you can move through panes you can use <code>Ctrl+b o</code> to go next pane. But again play with this keybindings list:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Ctrl+b % Split the window vertically
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b : Split the window horizontally
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b o Goto next pane
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b q Show pane numbers, when the numbers show up type the key to goto that pane
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b { Move the current pane left
</span><span class='line'>Ctrl+b } Move the current pane right</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p></p>

<p>There are a lot of keybindings for an advance use, like moving windows, resize panes, make panes into an own window, but you can see all these options in <code>Ctrl+b ?</code>. Help yourself.</p>

<p>At last but not least tmux can detach the whole session and re-attach it again if you want to.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>Ctrl+b d        Detach from currently attached session
</span><span class='line'>tmux attach -d  re-attach an attached session (detaching it from elsewhere)
</span><span class='line'>tmux attach     re-attach an attached session (keeping it attached elsewhere)</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>For sure it&rsquo;s not a hot technology but my ignorance about this kind of tool and how tmux does its job deserves a notable mention.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Old stuff becomes something new]]></title>
    <link href="http://willeeh.github.io/blog/2013/06/29/old-stuff-becomes-something-new/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-29T20:51:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://willeeh.github.io/blog/2013/06/29/old-stuff-becomes-something-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago I was working on an app to allow users to look for fast food restaurants in Spain. Actually, the app is pretty much done but I&rsquo;ve not published yet because of some minor design details. I&rsquo;m that kind of a good-eye guy who doesn&rsquo;t want to show the world the product til it&rsquo;s amazing, but I&rsquo;m becoming more <em>lean</em> lately.</p>

<p>I made a web scraper to get fast food restaurants info (as location, name, image,…) and then put into a database (I used MongoHQ btw). So, this weekend I uploaded the <a href="https://github.com/willeeh/food-franchises-geojson">code</a> to GitHub.</p>

<p>You can think: it&rsquo;s not a big deal anyway, so why &mdash;this boring&mdash; guy is talking about this?</p>

<p>Here we go… GitHub has launched a <a href="https://github.com/blog/1528-there-s-a-map-for-that">good feature</a> to visualize geographic data, using <a href="http://leafletjs.com/">Leaflet.js</a>, <a href="http://www.mapbox.com/">MapBox</a> and <a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a>. Ten days after this announcement they&rsquo;ve improved this feature letting <a href="https://github.com/blog/1541-geojson-rendering-improvements">large data sets to be grouped automatically</a>. Wonderful work!</p>

<p>That day I had no doubts I would use my code to generate GeoJSON to visualize fast food restaurants in Spain.</p>

<p>What do you think about this result?</p>

<script src="https://embed.github.com/view/geojson/willeeh/food-franchises-geojson/master/ALL_IN_ONE.geojson?height=420&width=700"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eh... What's up, doc?]]></title>
    <link href="http://willeeh.github.io/blog/2013/06/25/eh-dot-dot-dot-whats-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T22:18:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://willeeh.github.io/blog/2013/06/25/eh-dot-dot-dot-whats-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Here I am. </h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve proposed to myself blog something interesting every week at least. And you got a metapost here.</p>

<p>After seeing  <a href="http://nlopez.io/">mrmans0n</a> doing some great stuff with Octopress (blogging framework I&rsquo;m using in this blog), I wanted to give it a try and see how well was.</p>

<p>So good so far. Its documentation is pretty well, its simplicity is very sexy and deploying it on Github pages straight forward. But I miss some useful tools like remove posts not published yet. If I get used to work with Octopress, I will contribute this kind of tools.</p>

<p>In coming posts I promise to go deep into great stuff I&rsquo;m working on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
